Guide to the Richard Neville Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers, 1742-2011; Series I; 25.6; (62 boxes) + 1 art, 10 broadside, 1 roll
  - Dalton Thomas Walker Neville - photographs and clippings, circa 1919-1969; 2 (Box 31 (Oversize))
    Contains a photograph of Dalton Thomas Walker Neville, receiving a war medal. The caption reads "1000 marks - dead or alive". Also included are his 1969 obituaries.
  - Poster (draft) - with printing instructions (Box 31 (Oversize))
    Signed by Martin Sharp, circa 2005.
  - "Betty Neville" - day book, 1940-1946 (Box 31 (Oversize))
    Contains her journalism. The inside cover has Betty Neville's address, phone number and a note to return if found.
  - "Betty Neville beside cartwheel" - photograph, 1950s (Box 32)
  - "The Colonel's Mum", 1885 - photographic reprint (Box 32)
  - "The Neville devils, Singleton", 1900s - photographic reprint (Box 32)
  - Photographs (Box 32)
    Contains 29 photographs, including Andrew Fisher in SUDS, Richard Neville at Nimbin, Ken Neville (uncle), Louise Ferrier, Paul Jordan Smith (cousin), Betty Neville, Anne Cayzer, Suzette Markwell, Colonel Neville, and two transparencies -by Greg Weight- of Richard Neville on POL shoot, circa 1977.
  - Photographs (Box 32)
    Contains 17 photographs of the Neville Family, most notably Josie, Jill and children, and one portrait of Jill, July and Richard on the day of Richard Neville's arrival in London, September 1966.
  - "Duplicates" - photographs (Box 32)
    Contains 25 prints.
  - "Betty and Clive singing around the piano" - family photograph (Box 32)
  - Scandal: part 32 - "The Obscenity Trials", Chatterly and Oz., 1991 (Box 33)
  - "A draft of a memo by Felix Dennis re: the future of Oz" - edited typescript (Box 33)
  - Memorandum from Felix Dennis, 2009 March 3 (Box 33)
    Regarding the British Library's exhibition "Taking Liberties..."
  - Telegram from John Lennon and Yoko Ono (Box 33)
    Also includes the Apple Press release fax, a photocopy of the lyrics to "God Save Us / Do the OZ", and two photographs of John Lennon and Yoko Ono demonstrating at the Old Bailey.
  - "Australian student newspapers of interest, 1961-1973" - binder (Box 34 (Oversize))
    Contains facsimile copies of Tharunka, as well as copies of "the arty wild oat", volumes 1 and 2 (1962). It also contains the first issue of "Nimbin Good Times", which was produced as a guide to the forthcoming 1973 Aquarius Festival. The subsequent "Nimbin Good Times" issue is also included, volume 1, No. 1 (27 March 1973).
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1971 (Box 34 (Oversize))
    Contains clippings relating to Abbie Hoffman and Jerry Rubin.
  - "Oz archives A3 material of interest" - binder (Box 35 (Oversize))
    Contains newspaper clippings, and a small amount of correspondence.
  - Envelopes containing photographs and clippings, 13 (Box 36)
    Includes material regarding Louise Ferrier, Anne Cayzer, Julie Clarke, Betty Neville, Richard Neville's sisters and family, Richard Neville's youth, Colonel Clive Neville, various friends, Richard Neville's childhood, Yippies converging on Central Park, NY (1968), returning to Australia, the United States in 1972, and the Australian Oz.
  - "Studio script - Oz Trial" - for recording 1990 (Box 36)
  - Photograph album, circa 1970s (Box 36)
  - Felix Dennis / H. Bunch Associates memorandum, 1972 September 2 (Box 36)
    Regarding the rights to artwork, manuscripts, drawings and photographs in respect of published issues of Oz.
  - Richard Neville's opening address to the jury at the Old Bailey, Court 2, 1971 June 25 (Box 36)
  - "Oz Trial... rough draft" - early annotated trial memoir, circa 1970 (Box 36)
  - Annotated photocopies regarding Oz Trial and the 1971 appeal (Box 37 (Oversize))
    Contains papers, written statements, and legal transcript. Originally from the National Archives.
  - Annotated photocopies regarding Oz Trial and the 1971 appeal (Box 38 (Oversize))
  - "Oz special surprise issue" - poster, circa 1970 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Text is found on one side, and an illustration on the other, with images for the text "Plan a flower child".
  - Obscenity Trial ephemera, circa 1971 - photostat copies (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Contains photostat copies of ephemera and court documents relating to the Obscenity Trial (circa 1971). Includes an Oz Police Ball flier/ticket, a Soft Machine / Traffic benefit and trial souvenir programs.
  - Financial records, circa 1969-1974 - photostat copies (Box 39 (Oversize))
  - "The Oz Trial Souvenir Programme" - copies (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Facsimile Ink production department pages from Felix Dennis.
  - "Help Oz win at the Old Bailey and grow old gracefully" - poster, circa 1970 (Box 39 (Oversize))
  - "Communication with celebs", circa 1970-1971 - photostat copies (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Includes two letters from Richard Neville to Jim Haynes and a letter from John Lennon and Yoko Ono to Steve Tilston and Richard Howell.
  - "Oz obscenity trial at the Old Bailey, London", 1971 - photostat copies (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Photostat copies of designs for a sticker.
  - "Trial misc statements / notes", circa 1973 - photocopies (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Contains photocopies of documents regarding the Oz publication Ink, circa 1973.
  - Oz mock up - Felix Dennis, circa 1970 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Contains unbound sheets of a mock up prepared by Felix Dennis for use in a special number of Oz, to be issued after the trial. It recounts the entire event, from the first police visit to the acquittal and aftermath period. This was never published.
  - "The real Christine Keeler" - photographic copy (Box 39 (Oversize))
  - WWII soldier (C.H. Neville?) and young boy - photograph (Box 39 (Oversize))
  - WWII soldier (C.H. Neville?) and young boy - related documents, 1940s-1950s; 3 (Box 40)
  - Tharunka - bound volumes, 1962 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    Contains volume 8, No. 3 through volume 8, No. 11.
  - A3 photocopies / photostats of papers relating to the Oz Trial, 1970-1971 (Box 41 (Oversize))
  - Photographs / clippings (Box 41 (Oversize))
    Contains photographs and clippings relating to "En Route to London", "Pre trial London" and "London Oz trial photos".
  - Photocopies - Oz Trial, 1970-1971 (Box 41 (Oversize))
  - "Ink" related papers, circa 1970 (Box 41 (Oversize))
  - Criminal Investigation Department Report - photocopies, 1970 June (Box 42 (Oversize))
  - "Larrikins in London" - papers, circa 2001; 2 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    Contains papers relating to an exhibition in London, held in 2001. Also contains material regarding a related documentary, photographs, and a copy of a thesis by Eric Riddler entitled "Colonising London 1900-1970"
  - "NSW Design students' Oz covers" - photostats (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - "Memories and reflections of the Yellow House: 70/71 + newly discovered images of the 'Nimbin' experience, 1973 + rediscovered Sydney Oz prints" - binder (Box 44 (Oversize))
    Contains photographs and postcards.
  - Two mugs, decorated with Oz magazine covers (Box 45)
  - Typewriter (tan) (Box 46)
  - Valentine portable typewriter (red), circa 1969 (Box 56 (Art))
  - Large format scrapbook relating to Oz Trial, circa 1970 (Box 47 (Oversize))
    Contains clippings and a small amount of original correspondence in the form of postcards and letters, most in support of Richard Neville.
  - Large format scrapbook relating to Oz Trial, circa 1970 (Box 48 (Oversize))
  - Large format scrapbook relating to Oz Trial, circa 1970 (Box 49 (Oversize))
  - Large format scrapbook relating to Oz Trial, circa 1970 (Box 50 (Oversize))
  - Large format scrapbook relating to Oz Trial, circa 1970 (Box 51 (Oversize))
  - Large format scrapbook regarding political and social issues, 1960s-1970s (Box 52 (Oversize))
    Contains clippings.
  - Large format scrapbook regarding political and social issues, 1960s-1970s (Box 53 (Oversize))
  - Portrait photographs of Richard Neville, circa 1970 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    Contains six photographs.
  - Photo boards of Louise Ferrier, circa 1970 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    Contains three photo boards.
  - Black Dwarf - newspaper, 1968 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    Contains volume 13, No. 1 to Volume 13, No. 3
  - "Oz # 1 - copies of artboards" - material relating to Oz magazine, 2 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    Includes a poster and photostat copies
  - "Oz # 1" - material relating to Oz magazine (Box 54 (Oversize))
    Includes posters, photostat copies of covers, and photostat copies of artboards.
  - "Country Life: For Vital Rural News and Views" - billboard (Box 55 (Oversize))
    According to Richard Neville, this billboard is "the last relic / memento of the newspaper my father eventually managed".
  - Martin Sharp; Oz Intro Art; first Oz poster (Box 57 (Broadside))
  - Louise Ferrier, flower child London 1968 - color photographic print 440 x 440; Whitaker / Sharp Plan a Flower photographic print 650 x 430; Jenny Kee at Chelsea Antique market photographic copy 510 x 350 (3 pieces) (Box 58 (Broadside))
  - Four high resolution print: covers Oz 2, Legalise Pot Rally, Insert for Oz 18 and Independence Day Carnival power (5 pieces) (Box 59 (Broadside))
  - Trials of Oz poster; Taste of Oz poster; two states of the Oxford Playhouse production (4 pieces) (Box 60 (Broadside))
  - Cylinder annotated "Digital copies of Oz posters from Felix Denning" (7 pieces) (Box 61 (Broadside))
  - Cylinder annotated "Negatives of 'Hippie Hippie Shake' images (1995) Bloomsbury Edition" (4 pieces) (Box 62 (Broadside))
  - Large group of photostat copies relating to issue 28 "School Kids Issue" (Box 63 (Broadside))
  - Packet containing 5 x digital scans, printed newspaper banners of Oz Trial; Felix Dennis Archives - 13 x original newspaper banners. (Box 64 (Broadside))
  - Materials relating to Oz magazine - digital reproductions of covers and art boards (Box 65 (Broadside))
  - Materials relating to Oz magazine - posters (Box 66 (Broadside))
  - Cylinder annotated "Hippie Hippie Shake first editions film / images / post printer" (Box 67 (Roll))
    Comprises large sheets of film negatives, which appear to be proofs of the book.
  - "Decline and fall of the 60's: New York, Vol. 5, July 76 - May 77," manuscript (Box 74)
    In a three-ring binder.
  - Miscellaneous material removed from books (Box 75)
    Separated Materials
    Books removed and described separately.
  - Binders decorated by Richard Neville, previously containing printed material (Box 76)
    Printed material removed and described separately.
- Audiovisual materials, 1967-1975; Series II
  - The Trials of Oz: Oz 20 Years On and Dimbleby Intros, BBC Library Sales, studio discussion (PAL), undated; GENMSS862_0001; 1; 00:47:32; The timecode runs through the entire tape. (Box 68, Item barcode 39002102317543)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audiovisual Materials: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Items for Albie Thoms, BBC Resources, BBC News- Oz Trial (PAL), 2002 May 9; GENMSS862_0002; 1; 00:07:41; The timecode runs through the entire video. (Box 68, Item barcode 39002102317550)
  - Items for Albie Thoms, BBC Resources, Everyman, Where Have All the Flowers Gone? (PAL), 2002 May 9; GENMSS862_0003; 1; 00:37:14; A timecode runs through the video. (Box 68, Item barcode 39002102317568)
  - Items for Albie Thoms, BBC Resources, On Censorhip, Review, whole programme (PAL), 2002 May 9; GENMSS862_0004; 1; 00:07:48; A timecode runs through the video. (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317576)
    Includes paper BBC Recording Reports. Program is censorship of Oz prior to trial, Richard Neville, David Hockney, etc.
  - Screensound Australia, Darling Do You Love Me, 2003 March 7; GENMSS862_0005; 1; 00:05:19 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317584)
  - Screensound Australia, The Adventure of X, 2003 March 19; GENMSS862_0006; 1; 00:27:15 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317592)
  - Australian Broadcasting Corporation, Larrikins in London, Sidney Compile, undated; GENMSS862_0007; 1; 02:17:00; The video is damaged, but viewable. Timecodes run through the entire video. (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317600)
  - Untitled, undated; GENMSS862_0008; 1; 01:46:36 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317618)
    A note containing information about the tape's contents are included. It is difficult to read. It mentions NFSA clips; various 1960s.
  - BBC Worldwide, The Trials of Oz, Oz The Magazine and Dimbleby Intros, BBC Library Sales (PAL); Item 6, 1963; GENMSS862_0009; 1; 00:13:18; The timecode runs through the video. (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317626)
  - Screensound Australia, Ding a Ding Day, 2002 June 3; GENMSS862_0010; 1; 00:11:26 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317634)
  - Untitled, undated; GENMSS862_0011; 1; 01:06:24 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317642)
  - Screensound Australia, The Adventures of X, 2002 May 28; GENMSS862_0012; 1; 00:25:47 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317659)
  - Screensound Australia, Survey 14: Martin Sharp, 2002 May 29; GENMSS862_0013; 1; 00:32:56 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317667)
  - Screensound Australia, Trouble in Molopolis, 2003 March 19; GENMSS862_0014; 1; 01:15:49 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317675)
  - University of New South Wales, Audio Visual Unit, 64 Reunion, undated; GENMSS862_0015; 1; 00:15:37 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317683)
  - Sydney Underground Movies, Ubu Films 1965-1970, 1997; 1; 03:07:33; PAL (Box 69, Item barcode 39002102317691)
    Includes Albie Thoms' films "Blunders All," "Man and His World," "Rita and Dundi," "Moon Virility," "Bolero," "Boobs A Lot," "David Perry," and "Marinetti"
  - Original ABC Pederast program tape, undated; 1; 00:13:30; Program ends abruptly. (Box 77, Item barcode 39002091399692)
  - Richard + Andrea, 1968; 1; 00:19:46; The program is distorted at times. There is high background noise on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 77, Item barcode 39002091399700)
    A guitar is heard playing at about 07:41 until the end of the reel.
  - Cream, "Disraeli Gears," signed by cover artist Martin Sharp., 1967 (Box 72 (Record Album Storage))
  - Cream, "Wheels of Fire,"signed by cover artist Martin Sharp., 1968 (Box 73 (Record Album Storage))
- Computer media, Series III (Box 70)
  Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Electronic media, 3 (Box 70)
    Electronic Media: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - "ANDREA" INTERVIEW'S RICHARD N IN UK 1968 [ANDREA-1891-1985], 2011-genm-49148-0001; 1 (Box 78)
  - DAVID ELFICK USA photos AUST photos, 2011-genm-49148-0002; 1 (Box 78)
  - DVD RICHARD NEVILLE 1973 A KIND OF FREEDOM "AUSTRALIA'S CRACKER BARREL PIXIE" CLIVE JAMES, 2011-genm-49148-0003; 1 (Box 78)
- Restricted papers, 1976; Series IV
  Restricted until 2042. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Julie Clark correspondence, 1976 (Box 71)